Introduction
Chapter 1 Imagining a World Suddenly Free of People
Chapter 2 How Cities and Structures Begin to Crumble
Chapter 3 The Lasting Mark of Human Activity
Chapter 4 How Nature Recovers and Life Returns
Chapter 5 The Interconnectedness of Civilization and the Natural World
Chapter 6 Forests, Fields, and the Return of the Wild
Chapter 7 Oceans Unbound
Chapter 8 The Fate of Iconic Places
Chapter 9 The Persistence of Art and Culture
Chapter 10 The Long Shadow of Climate
Chapter 11 The Unseen World
Chapter 12 Lessons from Places Already Abandoned
Chapter 13 The Future of Evolution
Chapter 14 What Remains
Conclusion